DJINA PAJKIC

Address: 1000 Mount Pleasant Rd, # 1104, Toronto, ON M4P 2M2 **Phone**: 647.284.5579

Email: pajkic.djina@gmail.com

Personal Website LinkedIn Github

http://pajkicdj.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/djinapajkic https://github.com/pajkicdj

SUMMARY

I am a Junior Full Stack Developer with a background in Genetic Research from the University of Toronto (H.B.Sc). After four years of research experience that included data analysis using Python software, I have decided to transition into Web Development. I am addicted to fixing bugs, exploring new languages, frameworks, databases and designing beautiful UI/UX applications. I absolutely cannot wait to dig into an exciting project and begin expanding my career.

SKILLS

Technical: NODE.JS, JAVASCRIPT, AJAX, JQUERY, REACT.JS, REDUX, KOA, PYTHON, MATPLOTLIB, NUMPY ARRAYS, DATA ANALYSIS, D3, RUBY, RUBY ON RAILS, SINATRA, MYSQL, HTML5, CSS3, PHOTOSHOP, MICROSOFT OFFICE, ACTIVERECORD, POSTGRES, WINDOWS OS, MAC OS, HTTP/REST, GIT, SASS, RSPEC

Biotechnical: GENETICS, BIOTECHNOLOGY, MOLECULAR BIOLOGY, MAGIC TOOL ANALYSIS, QUANTITATIVE IMAGE ANALYSIS SOFTWARE, MICROARRAY CHIP TECHNOLOGY, MEGA4, NEXT GEN SEQUENCING, MSA, NCBI/BLAST, DNA, RNA, PROTEIN, PREPARATION AND HANDLING

EDUCATION

Honours B.SC. University of Toronto Toronto, ON 2014

Web Development Bootcamp

Lighthouse Labs Inc, Toronto, ON 2016

PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

CASTOFF - V1 & V2 - A Podcast Discovery App

(V1) Front-End, Back-End Development, & Design: Become addicted to the world of podcasts! Discover amazing new podcasts depending on your mood and favourite them for another time or to share with your friends! Developed using Ruby with the Sinatra Framework, HTML5 & CSS3. **(V2)** Remade with a React front-end and a Rails API.

ROTTEN MANGOES – A Rotten Tomatoes Replica-ish

Front-End, Back-End Development, & Design: Post your favourite movies, comment on any you like, meanwhile judging all your friends' taste in movies. Developed Using Ruby on Rails, HTML5 & CSS3.

CONTACT MANAGER - A Single Page Contact Organizer App

Front-end & back-end development: Keep everyone in your life organized! Add, update, remove anyone, it's easy. Built with Ruby within the Sinatra framework, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3.

PRINCESS KROFNE - Static Recipe Website

Front End Development & Design: Learn how to make this fluffy dessert to have fun, impress your friends or maybe just show off a little. Built with HTML, CSS & jQuery.

Natural variation in gene expression modulates the severity of mutant phenotypes

Validated RNAi data showing natural variation in the electron transport chain via potassium cyanide doseresponse curve variation.

A high-throughput image-based assay to measure the acute effects of drugs on C. Elegans

Generated and optimized software for high-throughput image data analysis through python programming. Illustrated that cyanide response varies over different developmental stages.

WORK EXPERIENCE & PRESENTATIONS

Jul. 2016 - Present

Full Stack Web Developer, GALE Partners

Web and mobile app development using React/React Native, Redux, Django, and Express.

Apr. 2016 – Jul. 2016

Full Stack Web Developer, Quartermaster

At Quartermaster, it was my responsibility to develop essential features using React + Redux, Koa, and Rails. I regularly consulted with senior developers as well as designers to manage large and complex projects for corporate clients.

Apr. 2013 - Dec 2015

Research Scientist and Lab Technician, Dr Andrew Fraser Laboratory – Donnelly Centre For Cellular And Biomolecular Research, University of Toronto

My full-time employment in Dr. Fraser's lab advanced my research experience involving the model organism C. elegans in regards to natural genetic variation research. I have aided and gained experience in developing assays, analyzing data using Python software, presenting data in a stimulating way and preparing data for publication.

Sep. 2013 - March 2014

Research Scientist and Student, Dr Andrew Fraser Laboratory – Donnelly Centre for Cellular and Biomolecular Research, University of Toronto

PROJECT - Study of Natural Genetic Variation in C. elegans via a Neurotransmitter Drug Screen Uncovers Two Drugs with Putative Variant Loci

Sep 2010 - April 2011

Vice President of Communications, Biotechnology Society, University of Toronto

I was elected as VP of communications for the Biotechnology Society at the University of Toronto. My duties included bringing awareness and educating students about the innovative and expanding field known as biotechnology through seminars presented by researchers within the industry and academia.

Sep 2012 – Feb 2014

Research Assistant, Dr. Marla Sokolowski Laboratory - Department of Cell and Systems Biology, UofT

Hands-on experience with fundamental molecular techniques, as well as familiarization with Drosophila rearing, has provided me with valuable research experience that I will require for further prospects.

Aug 2010

Volunteer, Sunnybrook Hospital, University of Toronto, Toronto

Through the volunteer program, I've witnessed the quality of care health professionals provide on a daily basis as well as the type of environment hospital life conveys. In addition to Sunnybrook, I've also volunteered at a number of academic events such as symposiums/conferences and talks held by researchers at the University of Toronto. Total number of hours: 250+